Zachary. what you doing?
The drawers stick.
Not for me. they didn't.
Morning. Ruby.
- Sticky drawers.
- Okay.
- Um. you missed a call.
- Who?
- Ten minutes ago.
- Thanks.
Ruby. Who was it?
- Hmm?
- Who was it?
None of your business.
This is Deputy Moretti.
Hey. it's good to hear your
voice. What's going on?
Work.
Yeah. me. too. Actually.
that's why I'm calling.
Looks like your department
put a flag on a Will Balint.
Name ring a bell?
- Yeah. it does. Why? What'd he do?
- He died.
Sheriff Wilkins
isn't at the office.
He's already headed to the
Cumberland County morgue.
Tell him we'll meet him there.
We'll meet him there.
So. what brings you
to Cumberland County?
This guy.
Oh.
I called them. Sheriff. I had
to because they never call me.
So. how'd he die?
Oil rig accident.
Overhead pipe slid
loose from its chain.
struck him in the back of
the head. knocking him out.
He fell face-first into
some mud. suffocated.
- How deep was the mud?
- Three inches.
Seriously?
Well. if you're unconscious.
that's plenty deep to
block your air passage.
Yeah.
- Anyone see this happen?
- No.
They didn't even find the guy until
one of the next fellas came on shift.
By then. it was too late.
What makes you so damned
interested in him anyway?
Will Balint is a suspect
in a recent rape case.
Seems suspicious he
now shows up dead.
Well. hell. he's
an oil rigger. Walt.
Newett Energy's actually got a
better safety record than most.
But with that drill turning 24/7.
there's bound to be accidents.
Remind me. Jim. you still
owe me a favor or is it my turn?
I lent you Eamonn. so I reckon
the next favor comes from you.
Might have to make it two. then.
Would you mind if I looked
around that oil rig a bit?
It's not your county. Walt.
I know that.
But if this death is a result of
something that happened in my county.
I can't help but feel
some responsibility here.
All right. You go
take your look.
But I'm sending Deputy
O'Neill here along as an escort.
I know how you get. Walt.
I don't want you forgetting that oil
company provides a lot of revenue
and a lot of jobs
in this county.
Will was a good worker.
Hell. he was better than
good. He was outstanding.
That's why I just promoted
him to assistant driller.
- What was Will's previous position?
- Roughneck.
Are those the guys whose job it
is to physically force young girls
into having sexual intercourse?
Those charges were dropped.
Or does "innocent until proven guilty"
only hold true in Cumberland County?
Walker. we're all just
trying to do our jobs here.
And our friends from Absaroka are
here with Sheriff Wilkins' blessing.
So. I need you to be as forthcoming
with them as you were with us.
Of course. My apologies.
It's just a little unsettling
to lose one of your own.
You know how that
is. don't you. Sheriff?
- Who found the body?
- Trot Simic.
Trot! Get up here. tell
them what you know.
Yeah. I clocked in. then I
walked up here to start my shift.
And I saw Will
laying in the mud.
- Was he dead when you found him?
- Yeah.
I mean. I tried to clear
his airway and do CPR.
You know. just in case.
But I couldn't remember how
many breaths for each push.
There ain't nothing you could do.
Don't beat yourself up on this one.
Yeah.
Where did this
accident happen. Trot?
Trot found Will right down there.
a 30-foot pipe right beside him.
I don't know if he got hit down there
or if he got knocked off the platform.
So. you just tossed
Will Balint's body aside
so you all could just
get back to work?
Look. everybody knows
what they're getting into here.
It's a dangerous job. People get
hurt. That's why it pays what it pays.
But if we were to stop production
every time there was an on-site accident.
however sad.
we'd immediately start hemorrhaging
hundreds of thousands of dollars.
We'd all be out of a job.
Speaking of which...
That's enough gossip.
boys! Go on. get back to work!
Just so you know. we did document
the scene and take statements
before Sheriff Wilkins gave the okay
for production to start back up again.
So you think it was an accident?
- I do.
Clearly. you don't.
What is it. just the
coincidence of the timing?
Walt doesn't believe
in coincidence.
There's also the
matter of that promotion.
Well. sure. A guy's new at his job.
he's more likely to make a mistake.
Especially if he
leapfrogs all the way up
from roughneck to
assistant driller in one day.
Is that weird?
Me and Henry spent most of our
20s working rigs up in Prudhoe Bay.
All those years. I never saw anybody
get made up from roughneck to AD
without being a derrickman
for at least a couple of years.
So what's so special about Will
Balint to make him the exception?
Well. let me take a look
at these guys' work records
and performance reviews.
That might explain things.
How are you gonna manage that?
I'll just tell them they can comply
with Cumberland's modest request
or I'll sic these two
Absaroka hard-asses on them.
Henry?
Hello. Cady.
- You look nice.
- Thank you. You don't.
Car trouble.
So. what is the occasion?
I'm going to meet a client
from one of the case
files that Mathias gave me.
Someone set fire to
Collin Burnside's house.
so I'm trying to push the
feds to open an investigation.
- Knock 'em dead.
- Thanks.
Wait. so. what
happened to Gab's rapist?
He got promoted. And
then he got knocked out
in a work-related accident and
suffocated in three inches of mud.
Wow!
Some coincidence.
You think someone was trying
to get revenge for Gab's rape?
If there was. we
need to figure out
who knew enough to even
identify Will Balint as a rapist.
Well. there's Gab. of course.
- Her mom. Linda.
- Yeah.
- May Stillwater and Gab's friend. Mandy.
- And us.
We can't take anything
for granted. right?
I mean. a badge and gun
doesn't make you flawless.
- You're right.
- He is?
Malachi.
His badge didn't keep him from
being a corrupt tribal police chief.
Malachi also knew
about Gab's rapists
after Mathias and I took a look
at the casino's security footage.
- Walt. You missed two more calls.
- I'll have to try back later.
You know. it's also possible
that this didn't have
anything to do with Gab's rape.
Vic said that Will Balint
was just promoted. right?
Maybe one of his co-workers
had a hard time with it.
Professional jealousy. you know?
Brings up hard feelings.
That's true.
Vic. I want you to drive back to Oden
and see if you can find Archer Loftus.
Who's Archer Loftus?
He's a roughneck
I met at the casino.
He's a whistleblower.
a conspiracy theorist.
If Ferg is right and this is about
internal politics at Newett Energy.
Archer will know about it.
Why do I have to go?
- It was Ferg's theory.
- Well. if memory serves.
you and Eamonn had the best
working relationship of any of us.
Zach. Ferg. I want you
two to put together a list
of all of Gab's close
family members and friends.
Anybody that may have been
motivated to see her rapists punished.
On it. How about you?
I think someone
needs to talk to Gab.
She deserves to know
that Will Balint is dead.
Thanks for coming.
I wanted you to be here
when Gab heard the news.
- What news?
- One of her rapists was killed.
Thank you for talking with us.
Gab. is your mom at work?
She quit last week.
- What's she doing now?
- Taking a vacation. Somewhere.
She bought this
TV before she left.
- When's she coming back?
- Check the freezer.
How many Lean Cuisines?
Six.
Six days. then.
What do you want?
We came to tell you
that Will Balint is dead.
Who's Will Balint?
He's one of the
men who raped you.
Which one?
The taller one.
Okay.
Back already. You must
have really missed me.
Walt wants me to talk to an oil worker
named Archer Loftus. You know him?
Ah. well. I've heard about him. He's
not the most popular guy around here.
No. that would be you.
- What are you talking about?
- Nothing.
Vic. come on. Obviously you're pissed
off about something. something about me.
No. No. I am
pissed off at myself.
'Cause I am so stupid. I thought
you wanted me to call you.
- I did.
- Really?
And who's the girl who answered
the phone when I actually did call?
When did you call?
Jesus. How many are there?
Maddie.
Who the hell is Maddie?
She's our Ruby. Except she's 22
and she's got a huge crush on me.
Wow! Have you always
suffered from self-esteem issues?
She has told me to
my face five times.
Every time she's had
more than one beer.
What are you two
doing back here?
Looking for Archer Loftus.
So am I.
This is Archer's bunk.
Co-worker reported him
missing just after you all left.
- When's the last time anyone saw him?
- 9:21 a.m.
That was what was on his time
card. Less than an hour into his shift.
- He ever split like this before?
- Nope.
But it was right
after we found Will.
It happens. The guys see
death up close and personal.
brings it home how
dangerous it is out here.
They freak out. they go AWOL.
Shit. As much as I'd like to stick
around and do your job for you.
I'm now two men short and
three hours behind production.
Don't let her take anything.
So. Archer Loftus takes off
right after they find the body.
What is that now.
three coincidences?
So...
Boots. jeans.
A few tools. nothing
too out of the ordinary.
"Cyrano Caballero"?
What is that?
A Big Sky matchmaker
for lonely hearts.
Which is exactly what I need.
What you...
- What's going on with this?
- With what?
You were with me when that
veteran insisted Hector was alive.
Now this.
Hector is dead.
We both know that.
Why does his name
keep coming up?
Why does it never
seem to surprise you?
This is what I look like
when I am surprised.
People are telling stories of
Hector coming back seeking revenge.
This car. for example.
belonged to Jack Mule Deer.
Jack was a drunk with a bad temper
who abandoned his family and sold meth.
Was? Somebody kill him?
Jack died last week
of a heart attack.
But some people choose to
believe that Hector made it happen.
Because out here. a death
like that feels like justice.
The kind that
Hector used to bring.
And so. in many ways. yes.
Hector lives.
As an idea.
And a hope.
Is it also possible that somebody's
taken up Hector's mantle?
If it is. Gab's mother might have
paid him off to kill Gab's rapist.
Anything is possible.
Nice to know we got
names and addresses
for most of Gab
Langton's family.
Should we combine our
lists. figure out a route?
Yup.
Okay.
Uh. where's. uh.
Old Kanaskat Road?
It's on the Rez.
I can't go there.
Okay.
418 Bramble Street?
Nope. No go.
Couldn't we just ask the
Rez police for permission?
Yeah. good luck with that.
Would you rather I started
making more mistakes?
Would that make you feel
more comfortable about yourself?
Or. or...
Or I could just. you know. keep
quiet. let you answer all the questions?
How you two coming with
that list of Gab's relatives?
It's not a rhetorical question.
Uh. Zachary. why
don't you go first?
Okay. uh... I think
we have a somewhat
complete list of her
relatives in the area.
- Let's hear them.
- Okay. It's Lem Langton.
Cordell Atherton. Emily
Strong Oak. Sam Poteet.
- Freddie and Janice...
- Wait. wait. Did you say Sam Poteet?
Yeah. why? It says here he's
Gab's father. Why? You know him?
Yeah. we know Sam Poteet.
And given the kind
of business he's in.
he's just the kind of guy
you ought to get to know.
- Why don't you come along?
- Yeah. yeah.
Think childbearing.
homemaking. lovemaking...
Show me all that in one picture.
Well. that is just as
sweet as the day is long.
- We're both consenting adults here.
- Congratulations.
But I'm looking for one of
your johns. Archer Loftus.
I'm not a fan of that term. I run a
legal. certified matchmaking service here
with a very highly
respectable clientele.
You are running an escort
service. and you and I both know it.
- I beg your pardon.
- Archer's contact information.
- Hand it over.
- Whoa. whoa!
If I granted access to my
clients' personal information.
it would be a
betrayal of their trust.
- Trust?
- Yes. Hello.
Really? Do you think that your
female clientele's gonna trust you
when they find out that you've been
setting them up with murder suspects?
What on earth... Bianca.
don't even begin to listen to that.
I screen my clientele
very carefully.
Archer Loftus was recently questioned
in connection with a local murder.
A young woman's body
was just found in a duffel bag
with Archer's luggage
tag attached to it.
Now. one of his co-workers
has been found dead
and he is suspiciously missing.
Do you really think
that that's the kind of guy
that Bianca here
wants to be set up with?
Probably not.
Fine.
If you can provide me
a proper search warrant.
I promise I will
not put up a holler.
But until then. I
am legally obliged
to protect my
clientele's privacy.
I do not have time for a search
warrant. I need the information now.
I know what you need.
You need a man in your life.
- is what you need.
- Excuse me?
I couldn't help but notice you don't
wear your wedding band anymore.
I could only guess
why that might be.
Okay. You know what.
Cyrano Caballero?
You're right. I need your
services. Sign me up.
I have standards.
And I have a cousin who works for
ICE. That's Immigration and Customs...
I know what ICE is.
Okay. Well. then you
would be motivated
to start me a dating profile
and send it to Mr. Loftus.
If you insist.
You might wanna take off
your little deputy costume.
Slip into something
a little more
you know. feminine.
Who's a pretty girl?
Well. look what was
under that big bear outfit.
Just give me the shirt.
You see. Walt.
how civilized this can be? No
warrants. no guns. no threats.
I just wanted to go about
this the right way. so...
It must be you...
- Zachary.
Well. you have a rather
calm energy about you.
Quite different from
your predecessor.
That energy must be
rubbing off on your boss.
Have a seat.
So...
You wanna go about
what the right way?
I'd like to speak to Sam Poteet.
We went by his house. but he's moved
out. There's no forwarding address.
I know he's done some work for
you. so I wanted to ask your permission
for us to talk to him.
I assume he's still working on
the casino hotel construction.
Why do you wanna talk
to one of my plumbers?
I have reason to believe that Sam
Poteet might be involved in a murder.
It has nothing to
do with your casino.
Happened up in Oden.
I see.
Well. I appreciate the
show of respect. Walt. I do.
But no.
Why are you
protecting him. Jacob?
He once stole a
dead body for you.
Is he doing other work for
you? Is he your new mercenary?
Is he the new Hector?
Oh. I don't know anything
about a new Hector.
No. I'm protecting Sam Poteet
because you have a badge.
a gun and power.
And Sam is a Cheyenne plumber
with no one else to look out for him.
So. now you're
protecting the powerless?
Because last week you
were preying on them.
What?
You've got Malachi and his thugs
running a loan-sharking
operation out of the casino.
And they robbed the people that owed
them money so they can't pay it back.
Your calming influence
seems to have worn off.
As has my patience.
Great to see you.
Thanks for stopping by.
Now. get the hell
out of my home.
Oh. Oh.
Hello. Zachary.
It's me. I need you to call the
Cumberland County morgue.
Find out if they've done
the autopsy on Will Balint yet.
Sure.
Uh...
Looking for anything
in particular?
Yep. Missing teeth.
So you were thinking that
Sam Poteet was the new Hector?
Mind if I ask who
was the old Hector?
Well. Hector was a former
boxer. lived on the Rez.
Whenever the
Cheyenne needed justice
and didn't feel they'd
get it through legal means.
they'd hire Hector to
knock some teeth out.
And you?
I thought Hector was a sign
that the system was broken.
Which is why I think there may
be a copycat version involved now.
We tried to follow the law.
but we couldn't get justice
for Gab after her rape.
So someone stepped outside of
the law. and one of her rapists is dead.
So. where are we going now?
To the casino.
To talk to Sam Poteet.
You know. I did try to
do this the right way first.
About what you saw earlier...
I. uh... I didn't see anything.
I...
Yeah. neither did I.
Uh. can I get a
room for tonight?
Just for yourself. or are
you expecting company?
No. just me.
I'd like a quiet room away
from the construction because
I'm a light sleeper. so...
Well. it looks like they're still
doing construction on the fourth floor.
but I can get you
into the second floor.
And I'll put you
in a king-size bed.
In case your luck changes.
Thanks.
They're installing plumbing in one
of the luxury suites down the hall.
Think a wrench like that could
loosen up a length of drill pipe
from a derrick chain?
Devon.
tell Malachi Sheriff
Longmire is trespassing.
A pipe on a derrick chain.
Is that a riddle?
I wanna talk to you
about your daughter.
I don't have one.
Okay. bye.
So. Gab Langton
isn't your daughter?
Sorry. I thought we
were talking white.
In our culture.
aunts and uncles are
also mothers and fathers.
We all have a responsibility
of taking care of all the children.
So. Gab's your niece?
No. she's my daughter.
Either way.
you know what happened to her.
Yeah. I do.
And I also know the
white men who raped her
went unpunished by
the white man's laws.
Now. one of those rapists just died in
an oil rig accident in Cumberland County.
Now I see.
When a young Cheyenne woman
is raped. your hands are tied.
But when a white rapist
is killed in another county.
suddenly you're on the warpath.
What's any of this
have to do with me?
Well. I was wondering if Gab's
mother sent you to kill that rapist.
She came into some money.
Maybe she paid for some justice.
Hector style.
Hector style?
I don't know what that means.
Well. they say there's a new
Hector working on the Rez.
And off.
And you do have a history of
doing illegal favors for people.
Hector was a Band-Aid. You can't
solve our problems one tooth at a time.
If we're going to reverse centuries of
genocide. we don't need a strong man.
We need an army.
Sam. where were you last night?
Sitting behind the moon.
Sheriff. if you're so concerned
about protecting these rapists.
you should hire a security
detail for the one who's still alive.
Because if our army has
already taken the field.
that asshole's not
going to last long.
We've been instructed to remove
you both from the premises.
Mr. Poteet. we apologize
for the interruption.
What's that?
That is rent money.
I was only supposed to be
here for a night or two. so...
Look. I know I'm supposed
to say something like.
"I can't accept that."
but frankly. I really
need it. so thank you.
What's going on?
I got a client.
That's a good thing. right?
It is. but photocopy costs and
trial fees are starting to add up.
and I cannot ask
my dad for money.
So. speaking of your dad. um.
how's his health?
Why?
He's just been getting calls
at the station from a doctor
and he never calls back.
so I'm just trying to figure out
if it's 'cause he doesn't want to
or if he's just caught
up in the Will Balint case.
Will Balint?
Gab's rapist?
You don't know?
Uh. he was found dead
over in Cumberland County.
He suffocated in a pile of mud.
We're thinking it
was a revenge killing.
So. questioning all the people
who knew the identities of the rapists.
It wasn't you. was it?
- No. no.
- Perfect. awesome.
- No. it wasn't me.
- Check that off my list.
- When did it happen?
- Mmm...
Earlier this morning.
- I gotta take this.
- Yeah.
This is Vic.
Victoria. Victoria.
Yeah. Oh. hi. how are you?
Tonight. yeah. No. of
course. yeah. that sounds fun.
Yeah. okay. I'll see you then.
All right. bye.
Who was that?
That was a guy named Archer
Loftus. He's one of our murder suspects.
and I got a date with him.
Eamonn?
Must be important for you
to drive all the way out here.
Yeah. it is.
Unfortunately.
Sheriff Wilkins has ruled
Will Balint's death an accident.
That was quick.
Well. Jim didn't find any
compelling evidence to the contrary.
Plus. he was getting
pressure from Newett Energy
to wrap up the investigation.
Newett Energy happen
to be a campaign donor?
They are.
And they paid for recent department
vehicle and weapon upgrades.
Now. for all we know. this
actually was an accident. but. um...
But what?
You were right to
question that promotion.
I looked at Newett's
employee reviews.
and Will Balint was completely
unqualified for that position.
The promotion should've
gone to Trot Simic.
The guy who found the body.
Archer Loftus have
anything to say about that?
Well. not yet.
we can't find him.
but Vic seems to
think she has a lead.
Where is Vic. anyway?
She's not answering her phone.
I don't know.
Why don't you try her on
her new home number?
I'm sure she'd be
glad to hear from you.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Anyway.
I'm sorry I don't have better
news. but I figured you should know.
- I appreciate it.
- Yeah.
Oh. uh...
Ferg wanted to know if Will
Balint was missing a tooth.
He was.
Must've gotten
knocked out when he fell.
Do you have that autopsy report?
Uh. no. it's not in there.
I probably shouldn't do this.
but I can have the
coroner fax over a copy.
- Thanks. Eamonn.
- Yeah.
I hope you still like fry
bread tacos and catfish pie.
So. Gab. did you ever
try writing to Hector?
Why?
For justice.
There's no Hector.
There's no justice.
- There's just good luck and bad luck.
- That is not true.
Hector lives.
- I promise you.
- Really?
Then why is one of those
men still walking around
like nothing even happened?
Perhaps you could change
this man's luck from good to bad.
Tell Hector what
this man did to you.
And where he can find him.
I'm not leaving the house.
I can't.
If you write to Hector.
I will deliver it.
Hector.
I don't know why
I'm writing to you.
Here's what I know.
There were two of them.
One didn't speak.
The other told me to
scream as loud as I wanted
because no one
cares enough to listen.
He was right.
Gab.
Archer!
- Archer. hi!
- Oh. hey.
- You Victoria?
- Yeah.
Oh. look at you.
All right. all right.
Wow!
You're even prettier
than your picture. Whoo!
- What was wrong with my picture?
- Oh. nothing. I wasn't saying that.
I was just saying that...
I should never open my mouth.
It's all right. My daddy always
said that I was too sensitive.
You go ahead and you say
whatever it is you wanna say.
Well. all right.
I do like to talk.
What do you wanna talk about?
Why don't we talk about
why it is that you fled
Newett Energy Oil Field
less than an hour after
a dead body was found?
- Shit moly!
- Shit.
Get out of my way!
Hey.
I'm looking for
Henry. Is he around?
Uh... I think I saw him wheel the
mop and bucket to the bathroom.
Thanks.
- We need to talk.
- In here?
Vic just told me that one of
Gab Langton's rapists died.
Under suspicious circumstances.
You hear about that?
Yes.
I was with Walt when
he gave Gab the news.
Oh. okay. Hey.
Piss outside!
Vic also told me that
they're looking for anyone
who might know enough
to target these guys.
I didn't tell them that you came
and asked me to look at their pictures.
Cady. I may not be a lawyer. but I think
I know an accusation when I hear one.
Will Balint died this
morning in the mud.
The same morning that you
came to work late covered in mud.
I'm not an idiot. Henry.
What's going on?
What is going on?
You mean besides the car
trouble I've already told you about?
For one thing. I used to be the proud
owner of a bar I built from scratch.
Now it is owned
by a man I despise.
I barely know who
I am some days.
And I would have thought
that you. of all people.
would understand
how difficult it can be
to have a calling and
not be able to follow it.
Cady. I have too much
respect for what you
and everyone else did to get me out
of jail to risk going back there again.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
So.
Archer.
I take it you're the kind
of worker who calls OSHA
about unsafe work conditions.
But this morning. when one of your
co-workers died on his shift. you...
Well. you didn't call OSHA.
You ran.
Why?
We already know you
clocked out at 9:21 a.m..
just five minutes after
Will Balint was found dead.
And you left without
collecting your things.
And then this evening. when I
showed you my badge. you fled.
Or you tried.
Now. if you don't have an
explanation for all of this.
we're gonna have no choice but to
charge you with Will Balint's murder.
If you did arrest me. how long
could you keep me in custody?
Up to 48 hours.
Here or back in Cumberland?
Well. it could be here.
All right. then arrest me.
Actually. now
that I think of it.
it might be better to release you
into the custody of your employer.
No. I'd prefer to be kept here.
Strongly prefer it. actually.
- Because you killed Will Balint?
- No.
Because you're afraid of
someone at Newett Energy?
Sheriff. if you want an
answer to a question like that.
you've gotta lock
me up in that cell.
And I don't want a Cumberland
County deputy in the room.
Okay. Thank you.
So. I went to work
yesterday. Normal morning.
Then I hear someone yelling
out of the mud pits for help.
By the time I get there. Trot
Simic is giving Will mouth-to-mouth.
But you could
tell it was too late.
He was already dead.
So I kind of freaked
out. and I left.
Why did you get so scared?
Will Balint came
to me last week.
He wanted to know where to go
when you don't feel comfortable
talking to your supervisor.
Who's your supervisor?
Walker Browning.
What'd you tell Will?
Well. I told him to speak to
someone in Human Resources.
The next thing I know. he
gets made all the way up
from roughneck
to assistant driller.
You worked rigs. you know
that just doesn't happen.
So. I figured. hey. they
must have bought Will off.
That is until he got killed. and I
realized what really happened.
They set him up in
order to silence him.
That's quite a conspiracy.
You mean like a
pretty. blonde cop
conspiring to entrap
someone on a dating service?
Yeah. I guess it is.
Crazy me.
Whatever Will told
these guys got him killed.
And. for all I know. they
think I know what Will knew.
So. I got the hell out of there
before they silenced me. too.
Who are you afraid
would try to silence you?
Walker Browning?
Walker doesn't
get his hands dirty.
Who do you think did this. then?
I don't know.
But Walker takes care of
those who take care of him.
Bonuses.
promotions.
I would be willing
to bet. though.
that whoever did kill Will is enjoying
a run of stupid good luck right now.
Whoo!
There he is. There he is.
There you go. gorgeous.
- Are those...
- Take one of those.
- Thank you.
- Squeeze on in there.
Squeeze on in.
There you go.
- No speeding. no drinking. Understood?
- Gotcha.
Don't stop until you
get to the reservation.
- Yes. sir. Mr. Browning.
- All right.
Be careful tonight. fellas.
These ladies look
awful frisky to me.
Yeah! MAN 2:
Here's to you. boss.
- You know it. boss.
- Have fun. All right?
Yeah. WOMAN: Yeah.
Looks like some lucky guys.
I don't know.
Right place at the right time.
Is that really luck?
I suppose not.
So. putting up that dating
profile to find Archer...
He's right.
That might be
considered entrapment.
Please. He was just thanking me.
I have never seen anyone so
excited to get locked up before.
He's clearly scared
shitless of Walker Browning.
He doesn't trust Eamonn.
Maybe he just doesn't
trust Eamonn's boss.
Apparently. Newett
Energy urged Sheriff Wilkins
to rule the death an
accident. which is strange.
Why?
Because a workplace accident opens up
the company to a big OSHA investigation.
Wrongful death
lawsuits. hefty fines.
But a simple murder is
outside of the company's liability.
They're free and clear.
So why insist on
ruling it an accident?
Unless you're trying
to cover up a murder.
Finally got Will Balint's
autopsy to print out.
How old is that fax
machine. exactly?
An autopsy report just made
a two-hour trip in seconds.
That's pretty good.
Huh.
What is it? Something to
do with that missing tooth?
No. No. it's something else.
Shall we beg you to tell us?
- Mud.
- Great.
That clears it up.
There was mud in Will Balint's
esophagus and his stomach.
Well. that doesn't
happen if he suffocated.
No. No. it doesn't.
If he inhaled mud. that
means he was conscious. so
he had his face in the mud.
someone was pushing him.
and he was trying to fight back.
So much for a drilling accident.
I also found out who got
promoted after Will died.
- Trot Simic.
- Yeah.
That sounds like a
run of stupid good luck.
- He also get a bonus?
- If he did. he's out spending it now.
Apparently. he went out to
celebrate his promotion tonight.
so we'll have to wait for
tomorrow to talk to him.
Maybe not.
I think I may know where
he's celebrating. Let's go.
Put it away. Heflin.
- This one's on me.
- The last one was on you.
Well...
Look. I owe you one.
I should. uh. be making
things easier for you.
Not making you feel like you've
gotta tiptoe around my ego.
No. no. no. it's cool. I...
I get it. You guys
are like a family.
A small. dysfunctional family.
I know it can't be easy trying to figure
out how to fit someone new into that.
All right. man.
Oh.
One second.
Hey. Ruby.
- Where are you?
- Oh. uh. Sheriff.
Uh... Sorry. I'm
at the Red Pony.
You been drinking?
A little.
Okay.
What? Uh...
- Over it.
- We're over it.
Hello? Yeah.
No. no. just a couple
of non-alcoholic beers.
I don't actually drink. so...
Casino?
All right.
Okay. who am I looking for?
Trot Simic. Okay.
All right. I'll be right there.
Sorry. man.
No. no. no.
Tell him. tell him.
- All right.
- Who needs a beer?
- Thank you.
You need a cigarette.
don't you? There you go.
- There you go.
- No. no.
You got one?
Are you doing all right?
- I'm looking at the stars.
- Oh.
The Pleiades.
Yeah. yeah.
My grandma used to tell me the legends
of their mother and her seven pups.
Well. you know. there's a
clearing back in the woods a way.
You can see the
whole sky from there.
You wanna grab these
beers and go over there
and tell me the story?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
All right.
I think we're crossing about
five jurisdictional lines right now.
You learn to get used to it.
Let's just focus on taking Trot
Simic into custody if he's here.
We'll sort out
the details later.
How much further until
we reach the clearing?
Well. we're already here.
We are?
There you go. There you go.
Come on. a little
dancing. Come on now.
Everybody. stop where you are. -
put your hands in the air.
This is bullshit.
- You've got no authority here...
- Put your hands in the air now.
Congratulations on
your big promotion. Trot.
Too bad Will's not here
to celebrate with you.
Maybe we ought to
move things to the station.
talk about why that is.
Stop it. What are you doing?
What do you think I'm doing?
No!
Hey. hey.
Whoa. whoa. whoa.
I'll get off her. just
leave me alone. all right?
Scream all you want.
No one will care
enough to listen.
If you ever step foot on this
land again to hurt another woman.
I won't just take your teeth.
I'll take your life.
- Did you hear that?
- Stay here.
Gab?
Gab. we have to run.
I'm sure someone
heard the gunshot.
We have to run.
Gab.
Run.
Give me the gun.
I dropped it back there.
Go.
Sheriff's Department!
Stop!
Stop or I'll shoot!
English -SDH